ultimatetopsites.com 2017-06-25

# Privacy Statement

##  Privacy Policy for Ultimate Topsites 

The privacy of our visitors to Ultimate Topsites is important to us. At Ultimate Topsites, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit [Ultimate Topsites](http://www.ultimatetopsites.com/), and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties. 

####  Information Automatically Logged In Log Files 

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer, Chrome, or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. We will use I.P. addresses to identify users of our site when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our site's [terms of use](http://www.ultimatetopsites.com/bin/create/terms.html) or to protect our service, site, or other users. 

####  Cookies and Web Beacons 

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums. We also use third party advertisements on Ultimate Topsites to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). 

#### DoubleClick DART Cookies

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts. Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added. 

####  Personal Information 

This Web site does not request any personal information or collect any information that personally identifies you or allows you to be personally contacted. 

Since we do not collect any personal information on this Web site, we do not share any personal information with any third parties nor do we use any personal information for any purposes. 

####  External Links 

This site contains links to other sites. **Ultimate Topsites** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

####  Public Forums 

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

####  Security 

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. All Ultimate Topsites passwords are encrypted. That means nobody can ever see your password, not the owner of the Topsites or Ultimate Topsites administrators.
